all right make this video quickly which
I wish to quickly it's about five
minutes and I post the first take
I wanted to talk about social anxiety
which I have and I've realized the
solution for myself is radical
acceptance that I'm awkward okay with
that that I say the wrong thing at the
wrong time and I single-sided deafness
makes me awkward because people talk to
me on one side I don't do well in large
social situations and I've been doing
much better not in that have to do
better in social situations but that I'm
gonna probably have but I've been more
accepting of myself so what used to be
like weeks of me obsessing about
something I said is like a second so I
feel that like icky feeling and I'm like
you know at least that like you don't
need to pull onto that if you said
something actually problematic can't
think you offended someone and you don't
want to have offended someone then
apologize otherwise let it go they're
probably not thinking about it and part
of that is I think we're all exactly
that we're supposed to be so I'm
supposed to be socially awkward
I'm very strongly feel that I'm exactly
who I'm supposed to be to do what I need
to do on this planet and so is everybody
else
and we need to embrace our weirdness and
one of the things one of the parenting
Facebook groups I'm part of which is
amazing had someone talking about their
child and how they were socially awkward
as a kid and overweight and they worry
about their kid having the same the same
problems and I strongly believe we need
to change the world my child is not
socially awkward to me she's four so
she's still learning a lot of things
about boundaries and personal space and
consents and stuff but she makes friends
everywhere she goes because I've just
gotten out of her way and haven't put on
the same steak my parents maybe put on
me of like well don't do that that's not
gonna make friends and don't do that I
just let her be her amazing self and I
do we do talk about kindness and about
inclusion and and helping other people
and how she's so social and makes
friends so easily and other people
don't so maybe she can reach out to
those people and just be aware of it and
I think the more people with socially
advanced it's wrong word but like
socially advanced children the more were
able to put out there make the world a
better place I mean I don't want to beat
my kid into a mold so they don't get
picked on I need her to be strong enough
that she can be her true self and not
care what the world says because you
can't be liked by everyone you'd be
really boring if you were liked by
everyone and it's taken me into my 30s
to realize that truly to truly get that
at a soul level that to find my people
to find my community to find my soul
mate or soul mates I have to be me
because the good the bad all of it
because there is no if you fake it if
you're trying to be something you're not
you're constantly striving to be more
and striving to be different you're not
being you we don't need any a world
automatons that are all that are all
exactly the same we need to accept
people for for who they are and that's
my solution to social anxiety
I think another piece of that is Trump
and realizing I mean I really dislike
Trump but I also see him as possibly the
most positive thing to be happening on
this planet at the moment not because
he's positive he's doing horrible
horrible things but the catalyst he's
being for change
assuming he doesn't start a nuclear war
with North Korea it's just so it's
driving so many people to come together
and realize that we can't trust our
governments in the way we maybe have up
to this point and we can't trust the
systems and he's such a repulsive human
being but he's exactly who he's supposed
to be and maybe in the moment when I say
something stupid and I might offend
someone and I trigger them and write
maybe it's supposed to happen maybe and
I'd miss me go up there and be a troll
and do things horribly I always come try
to come from a place of love and
acceptance and understanding and
sometimes it doesn't come off that way
and to still examine it but not
to it and something I'm working on on a
regular basis but I feel more free now
my anxiety has greatly reduced with just
the acceptance the radical acceptance of
all of my quirks and all of my stuff I
definitely got triggered yesterday
because I went to my child's new school
and I know a lot of the parents that go
there and their kids and it's just I
don't do well in big loud environments
and I always feel socially awkward
because it's like I can't really have a
conversation and get to know people or
even talk to people I already know in
that situation so then I feel like I'm
being snob it's a stop and or I say the
wrong thing or I interrupt people's
conversations or I'm involved in a
conversation maybe I shouldn't be or I
don't know it's just socially awkward
and but I also realized the people that
I know there are democratic school so I
don't know how in charge anyone is the
parent unit but they are they're the
people who are like running around doing
stuff who were part of like sitting up
with the friends talking more about
stuff 300 the six people that I know and
then the other ones were also like more
vocal at the meeting than other people
that I was surrounded with myself
without knowing it with the top well
some of the top people at the school and
I wonder how in my life I've also maybe
done the same and not realized it that I
do have people surrounding me that are
they were amazing and sort of one
compare myself to none probably isn't it
great a great solution because I'm not
gonna feel adequate and to that's
powerful in and of itself and so yeah
I'm just sitting with that today and
realizing that my social anxiety like my
disability like being a single parent
like all everything that's happened in
my life that maybe I wouldn't have
chosen as a child some of my dream is
exactly who I need to be on this planet
to create this global cooperative that
I'm creating and together we're gonna
find the solutions to this planet thank
you